

# Saurabh Doshi

Reach me on: +91-7575060601 Email doshisaurabh1@gmail.com

# HIGH IMPACT TALENT AQUSITION & HUMAN RESOURCE PROFESSIONAL

#### TALENT AQUISITION EXPERIENCE BIFURCATION



## **AREAS OF EXPERTISE:**

Business Analysis
Executive Search
International Talent Acquisition
Domestic Talent Acquisitions
Strategic planning
New Market Penetration
Branding & Advertising
Client Relationship Management
Microsoft Office(Outlook, Word, Excel, Powerpoint)

#### **PEARSONAL DETAILS:**

Date of Birth :13/06/1982
Nationality : Indian
Marital Status : Married

Language Skills : English, Hindi, Gujarati & Bengali

#### RECOGNITIONS

Received Recognitions awards for achieving Highest Revenue of company for Continue 5 times in a row since Oct 2015 to till Mach 2018

Received Recognitions awards for Best Team mentor Twice in span of 2 Years..

Recognitions from the group for initiation of Providing a local African talent in Africa.

Received Recognitions for placing Diaspora candidates to different part of Africa.

## **CAREER SYNOPSIS:**

HR professional proficient in Recruitment & Talent Acquisition. Proficient in managing relationships for running successful Talent Acquisition for business excellence.

HR professional with a flair for charting and implementing Talent Acquisition process & strategies and contributing towards enhancing business growth and profitability in India Africa and emerging markets with over 16 years of experience.

## **EDUCATION DETAILS:**

2004: **Bachelor in Commerce (Advance Accounting)** from Gujarat University .

### TRAINIG PROGRAMME ATTENDED

Feb 2015: **LinkedIn** training for sourcing Passive Professionals from across the globe.

Jan 2011: BEST YEAR YET

#### **CAREER DETAILS**

BDHRS Talent 4.0 Pvt Ltd (formerly Known as Datum Recruitment Service Dec 2012 – Till date

BDHRS Talent 4.0 Pvt Ltd is an International Employment Agency specializing in recruiting for jobs in Africa. Company provides Executive Search and Staffing Solutions for Middle Management and Executive Level jobs in Africa and help expatriates and locals build fulfilling careers in Africa.

## **Growth Path:**

April 2017 - Till Date : Manager Recruitment & Client Serving

Dec 2012 - March 2017 : Asst. Manager Recruitment

# **Key Deliverables**

#### Recruitment

- Responsible for Full cycle of recruitment (End-to-End) for India, Africa and Emerging Markets
- Consulting support to all business units for their project based recruitment
- Optimize delivery of recruiting; achieve milestones of business critical hiring needs with significant cost savings recruitment tools.
- Policy and Process Design, Implementation and Review for recruitment processes.
- Client Relationships Management
- Candidate Relationship Management
- Reviewing and qualifying job descriptions provided by chiefs / MD / Directors and recruiting qualified and talented
  candidates across various clients in National and International staffing model.
- Strategy development for-Search, headhunting, company mapping.
- Responsible for conducting Interviews for seniors and middle level managements.
- Works closely with clients for successful on-boarding and off-boarding of all verticals professionals with the agreed methodology.
- Responsible for entire recruitment cycle for National and Internationals Markets. Process including writing Job description Sourcing and identifying candidates from across the globe, telephone / Skype / VC screening, in-person interviews for Indian candidates, conducting follow-ups, presenting offers and negotiating salaries.
- Reference checks and prepared candidates for hiring managers.
- Team Management
- Maintaining and upgrading the manual and computerized filing systems and data base, Reports preparation.

## **Training & Development:**

- Identification of Training Needs through Performance Appraisal system.
- Identification of Internal Trainer.
- Post Training Evaluation.
- Induction Training for new joinee

## **Business development:**

- Market research for business expansion and developing new clients for Emerging Markets.
- Meeting clients and building partnership to serve their recruitment needs.
- Building Market position by locating, developing, defining, Negotiating and closing Business Relationships.
- Acquiring New Clients across Africa and South East Asia.
- Interfacing with Clients and cultivating healthy corporate relations with them for securing repeated business

#### **Dhruv Corporate (HR) Solutions Pvt Itd.**

November 2002 to October 2012

Dhruv Corporate (HR) Solutions Pvt. Ltd. Is a professionally managed Executive Search and Selection company, has established itself as a reliable partner in recruitment - nationally and internationally.

# **Key Deliverables**

#### Recruitment

- Heading the Finance & Accounts, IT & Overseas Vertical.
- Responsible for the top & bottom-line for all 3 vertical
- Responsible for Full cycle of recruitment (End-to-End) for Overseas & Domestic Markets.
- Client Relationship Management.
- Understanding new requirements and managing the work allocation.
- Developing strategy for-different types of candidate sourcing.
- Responsible for scheduling interview, salary negotiation and solving queries/ concerns of candidates.
- Management Information System (MIS) for allocated clients.
- Work allocation to team members and managing performance of the team

- Recruitment of team, induction of new entrants, identification of specific individual training needs based on their performance.
- HR Documentation and maintaining database

## **Business development:**

- Market research for business expansion and developing new clients for Emerging Markets.
- Meeting clients and building partnership to serve their recruitment needs.

**REFERENCE DETAILS:** Available on Request